<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <atom:link href="https://www.cem.me/cem.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <title>CeM - Carl Mehner's Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.cem.me/</link>
      <image>
        <title>CeM - Carl Mehner's Blog</title>
        <url>https://www.cem.me/favicon.png</url>
        <link>https://www.cem.me/</link>
      </image>
      <description>Carl Mehner's Blog on Security, PKI, and computers</description>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <generator>by hand in vim</generator>
      <managingEditor>c+blog@cem.me (Carl Mehner)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>c+blog@cem.me (Carl Mehner)</webMaster>

   <item>
        <title>Certificate Binary Posters (Part Six)</title>
	<link>https://www.cem.me/20150315-cert-binaries-6.html?s=r</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
		<p>One thing that is <a href="https://www.cem.me/20141221-cert-binaries.html">noticeably</a>, <a href="https://www.cem.me/20150104-cert-binaries-2.html">different</a>, <a href="https://www.cem.me/20150121-cert-binaries-3.html">from</a>, <a href="https://www.cem.me/20150209-cert-binaries-4.html">previous</a>, <a href="https://www.cem.me/20150301-cert-binaries-5.html">posters</a> is that these formats are not encoded in base64, they are binary files. Most of the other files can be interpreted by cryptosystems in both binary and base64, and we typically transport them by first encoding them in base64.</p>
		<p>In these formats, in order to show the binary in a visual representation I used <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Netpbm_format#PGM_example">Netpbm</a> (<b>Net</b>work <b>p</b>ortable <b>b</b>itmap for<b>m</b>at) with the PGM (<b>P</b>ortable <b>G</b>ray<b>m</b>ap) format to translate the hexadecimal values into a format easier for humans to visualize. (A more fun format would be to <a href="https://gist.github.com/windytan/7910910/">use emoji</a>, but that would not fit quite as well with the rest of the poster).</p>
<img src="https://www.cem.me/art/emoji.png" alt="emoji pfx" />vs<img src="https://www.cem.me/art/pgm.png" alt="pgm jks" />
<p>Microsoft came up with the pfx format (which was later changed slightly and reworked as PKCS &#35;12), and recieved <a href="https://www.cs.auckland.ac.nz/~pgut001/pubs/pfx.html">much criticism</a> due to the complex nature, terminology, and internal formats. At first glance the p12 format seems to be fairly complex, it includes many wrappers of wrappers that enclose keys, certificates, and descriptive data. The reason for all of those is that pfx files can contain (according to Gutmann), "CRL's, keys, names, cookie recipes, dirty laundry, spare lightbulbs, and the kitchen sink". However, for storing certificates and a private key in pfx, it is really just a list of pairs of encrypted certificate chain and the associated encrypted key. </p>
<p>The keys and certificates in the pfx are stored in separate containers and encrypted with different keys and most of the time different algorithms also.</p>
<p>When using Windows, there really is no way around the algorithm used. The default is to encrypt the certificates with RC2 and the private key with 3DES, this means that the highest strength you would ever be able to achieve is equivalent to 3DES. However, on OpenSSL, you can specify the encryption algorithm for both the key and the certificates to use the stronger AES-256 by adding additional flags:<br />
<code>-certpbe AES-256-CBC -keypbe AES-256-CBC</code></p>
<p>Of course, at the moment, the strength is predominantly up to the password used as the best way to defeat even the Windows version is to use a password list. This is somewhat slowed by the number of rounds the key derivation algorithm is passed through; 2000 on pfx files generated via Windows and 2048 by default from OpenSSL.</p>

<a href="https://plus.google.com/photos/+CarlMehner/albums/6105920604274654785/6126635201442771314"><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-rrlIl-yMdis/VQYuQWJmcXI/AAAAAAAAGGM/H2J-MCRKurM/s800/p12.png" alt="pfx"/></a>

<p>Java has its own proprietary format that it named JKS, which stands for Java KeyStore.</p> <p>While the p12 format is binary encoded ASN.1, jks format files are a strange mix of binary and ASN.1. The file begins with a "magic number" as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_file_signatures">many other</a> binary files do. After that comes a list of different keys or certificates. JKS files are also quite extensible and are able to hold many objects, including lists of chains, certificates, roots, as well as lone private keys. The number of keystore entries is defined at the beginning of the file and the data is listed in a serialized manner. For this example of just an x.509 certificate and key, the entry contains: a plaintext alias, encrypted private key, and plaintext chain.</p>
<p>Unlike pkcs12, you cannot choose the algorithm used to protect the keys, so everyone is stuck with a proprietary implementation of a password based key derivation scheme using MD5 to create a 3DES key. </p>

<a href="https://plus.google.com/photos/+CarlMehner/albums/6105920604274654785/6126635193771531266"><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-eK-jRz45vyY/VQYuP5konAI/AAAAAAAAGGI/Uk5pMfTQYW0/s800/jks.png" alt="jks" /></a>

<p>The moral of the story, is use a long and complex password for either of these formats. Even so, if your keystore does get out, you will need to revoke your certificate. More on that next post.</p>

		]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 03:16:16 -0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://www.cem.me/20150315-cert-binaries-6.html</guid>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Certificate Binary Posters (Part Five)</title>
	<link>https://www.cem.me/20150301-cert-binaries-5.html?s=r</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
<p><small>Previous Posts: (<a href="https://www.cem.me/20141221-cert-binaries.html">Part One</a>, <a href="https://www.cem.me/20150104-cert-binaries-2.html">Part Two</a>, <a href="https://www.cem.me/20150121-cert-binaries-3.html">Part Three</a>, <a href="https://www.cem.me/20150209-cert-binaries-4.html">Part Four</a>)</small></p>
  <p>Certificates used in webservers and other end-entity uses are signed by issuers (which should not be root CAs, but it is possible). However, there are a lot of issuer certificates; in 2010 there were <a href="https://www.eff.org/files/ccc2010.pdf">nearly 1500</a>, now certainly more are out there with <a href="https://letsencrypt.org">more planned</a>. Because there are so many undistributed issuing CAs, there needs to be a way for the CA to send the issuer cert to the cert requester along with the end-entity certificate so they can pass that along to anyone that needs to validate their root. One of the common ways to pass public keys for a specific chain is the PKCS #7 format. This format is a way to ensure that the right certificates are used in the chain for the particular server certificate.</p>
  <p>PKCS #7 begins, as all the others have, with a sequence of the encoded data and length. Immediately following is the OID for PKCS #7 signedData content type. This specifies the type of the content of the p7 object. The content is put into an explicit object that contains a sequence which wraps the object. Inside, the signedData object the structure begins with a version, digest algorithm identifies (empty here), a content info (here specifying the OID for PKCS #7 data), certificates, crls (empty here), and lastly another empty field that can hold additional information on signers.<p>
  <p>The certificates field is an ASN.1 explicit type wrapper which contains x.509 sequences as they appear in the x.509 posters from <a href="https://www.cem.me/20150209-cert-binaries-4.html">part 4</a>.<p>
  <a href="https://plus.google.com/photos/+CarlMehner/albums/6105920604274654785/6108892209146183330"><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-Mty_nrd3MaE/VMclGRFPPqI/AAAAAAAAGDs/A5j19DmJmwI/s800/PKCS7.png"  alt="p7b" /></a>
		]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 06:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://www.cem.me/20150301-cert-binaries-5.html</guid>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Certificate Binary Posters (Part Four)</title>
        <link>https://www.cem.me/20150209-cert-binaries-4.html?s=r</link>
	<description><![CDATA[

  <p><small>If you missed the previous posts, you may want to read them first (<a href="https://www.cem.me/20141221-cert-binaries.html">Part One</a>, <a href="https://www.cem.me/20150104-cert-binaries-2.html">Part Two</a>, <a href="https://www.cem.me/20150121-cert-binaries-3.html">Part Three</a>)</small></p>
  <p>After the certificate authority (CA) receives the <a href="https://www.cem.me/20150121-cert-binaries-3.html">CSR</a>, it signs it, then sends back the TLS cert. You can see two places in this certificate that directly correspond to the CSR (the public key and the DN). There are three main sections within the certificate wrapper: the tbsCertificate data (tbs = to-be-signed), the structure the specifying signature used to sign the cert, and the signature value. The CA crafts the tbsCertificate from the data given in the CSR, adding additional fields before copying the DN and SPKI (subject public key info; aka the PKCS#1 object).</p></p>The tbsCertificate starts out with a version container with a version byte, and as with all of the valid TLS certs trusted on the Internet right now, is version 3 (notice the value of 2 on the left due to the 0-based version index). Next the serial number of the cert which because this is an example is shortened, normally it will be <a href="https://cabforum.org/wp-content/uploads/BRv1.2.3.pdf">at least 20</a> random bits. The next field is byte for byte the same as the certificate's signature algorithm ID mentioned above. Following that, the name of the CA that signed the cert goes to the issuer section. The CA's DN sequence is copied to the issuer field of any certificates it signs. The CA also controls the validity dates, the UTC time elements are normally set with the start as the current time, or current GMT date at midnight, with the end date set to a max of 3 years and 3 months (or for extended validation (EV) certs 2 years and 3 months). However, they can be set to nearly any date in the future or in the past. Finally, the DN and SPKI are copied from the CSR and tacked on to the end.</p>
  <p>Up until now, all of the fields are in x.509v1 certificates, the difference between version 1 and version 3 certificates are that v3 includes the extensions section below the SPKI. Extensions allow for, as the word implies, extensibility. You can have as many or as few extensions as are required, they can be marked critical or noncritical. A critical extension must be understood by the validating software, otherwise the certificate validation must fail. There are rules set by the CA / Browser Forum for which extensions are required for inclusion and which to mark as critical. In this example, (which only follows some of the rules) there is an extension requiring the certificate to be an end-entity (that is not a CA) as well as the AKI (authority key identifier). An AKI is a way to tie a specified end-entity certificate to the certificate that issued it.</p>
  <p>Lastly, the specified signature algorithm uses the CA's private key to sign the bytes from the tbsCertificate, the result is the signature value.</p>

<a href="https://plus.google.com/photos/+CarlMehner/albums/6105920604274654785/6108892262647630978"><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-6zdPndot6Iw/VMclJYY-jII/AAAAAAAAF-k/n9btf1nPf_A/s800/x509.png" alt="x.509 certificate" /></a>
 
		]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 04:04:04 -0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://www.cem.me/20150209-cert-binaries-4.html</guid>
    </item>


    <item>
        <title>Certificate Binary Posters (Part Three)</title>
	<link>https://www.cem.me/20150121-cert-binaries-3.html#</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
	  <p><small>If you missed the previous posts, you may want to read them first (<a href="https://www.cem.me/20141221-cert-binaries.html">Part One</a>, <a href="https://www.cem.me/20150104-cert-binaries-2.html">Part Two</a>)</small></p>  
  <p>This first part is a building block for more wonderful things to come. The Distinguished Name for x.500 are the basis for identity and trust on the Internet. You may notice that the base64 in the upper left is a certificate request, I highlighted the bytes to pull out of that to show this detailed view in order to clarify this more complex block. Each of the names in the that make up the distinguished name are an ASN.1 'set' containing a 'sequence' of the attribute type and the value of the attribute. The attribute type is an OID (Object IDentifier), a hierarchical structure used to describe namespaces. All of the OIDs here are under the x.500 attribute types namespace. Second within the set, after the OID, is the value associated to it: country, state, local, et seq. This is encoded in the UTF-8 (<b>U</b>niversal Character Set + <b>T</b>ransformation <b>F</b>ormat).</p>
  <a href="https://plus.google.com/photos/+CarlMehner/albums/6105920604274654785/6105920707666080834"><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-gG1aAE7ovog/VLyWiHcjdEI/AAAAAAAAF8U/xzhuasDqrGQ/s800/DNx500.png" alt="x.500 - DN" /></a>
  <p>The base64 in the top left of this next poster is the same as the last, however, as the last focused on the DN, this focuses on most of the rest. I say most because the sequence immediately following the DN is a PKCS#1 object. This is the same thing I went over at the end of <a href="https://www.cem.me/20141221-cert-binaries.html">part one</a>.</p>
  <p>CSRs are sent to a certificate authority which they then use to produce a signed certificate for use in TLS to secure websites, or any number of other x.509/PKI applications.</p>
  <p>The entire CSR is contained in one large sequence. Within that is a sequence of request data followed by the CSR signature algorithm and lastly the signature value.</p>
  <p>The request data is made up of a version (value of 0, meaning of 1; <small>remember computer scientists count from 0...</small>), the DN above (which specifies the request identification information), after that is the PKCS#1 object (identical to the PKCS#1 public key poster). Lastly is the attributes section, here it is empty. The attributes are defined in a PKCS#9 objects. This field is little used now, but at one point it was used to add passwords that the requestor would have to provide at the time of revocation to authenticate to the revocation system.</p>
  <a href="https://plus.google.com/photos/+CarlMehner/albums/6105920604274654785/6105920735563250578"><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-RAXYcgi2FuE/VLyWjvXwe5I/AAAAAAAAF8c/0zAYKNR0YY4/s800/p10.png" alt="pkcs10" /></a>
  <p>Next, what the certificate authority sends back.</p>
		]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 02:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
	<guid>https://www.cem.me/20150121-cert-binaries-3.html</guid>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Certificate Binary Posters (Part Two)</title>
        <link>https://www.cem.me/20141221-cert-binaries-2.html?s=r</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
  <p><small>If you missed the previous post, you may want to read that first (<a href="https://www.cem.me/20141221-cert-binaries.html">Part One</a>)</small></p>
  <p>The previous post shows one way to store private keys, the PKCS#1 format. This post shows a different format, PKCS#8. This format is more extensible, allowing for more than just the one type of key to be stored. This format splits up the private key representation into three sections: a version, an algorithm identifier, and the actual private key. The version is set at 0, and may eventually change if there are any updates to the standard. The algorithm ID is an OID defined as "RSA Encryption" for use with the PKCS#1 standard. That is to say, the very same standard we went over in the previous post. The last part is a wrapper for the PKCS#1 private key object. This is the exact same thing byte for byte as the PKCS#1 private key.</p>

  <a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/6zamMivAFuluJ1V-6_GLW9MTjNZETYmyPJy0liipFm0?feat=embedwebsite"><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-okA540VQO9Y/VKoiagfxR5I/AAAAAAAAF6c/19IW110wZek/s800/pkcs8nocrypt.png" alt="private key" /></a>

  <p>Unprotected private keys like that are not the best thing to keep laying around, luckily, there's another version of the PKCS#8 which holds an encrypted version of the private key. This format is broken into two pieces, an encryption algorithm and the encrypted data. The encryption algorithm starts with the algorithm identifier for the Password Based Encryption Scheme. The next section is a container for the parameters and data needed to derive the encryption key. For this example I chose to use the Password Based Encryption Scheme #2 (better known as PBKDF2). Fed into the BPKDF2 are the salt, the number of times to run the pseudorandom function over the passphrase used to encrypt the key. Next is the encryption scheme, AES-256-CBC and the initialization vector for the AES algorithm. The key resulting from the PBKDF2 and the salt are fed in as parameters to the AES function along with the message found in the encrypted data section. The result of the decryption is a BER (Basic Encoding Rules) encoded octet string. An octet string you may recognize from above (hint: it's the private key sequence).</p>

  <a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/UMWSoooFF6Z2LPrn7jqMQ9MTjNZETYmyPJy0liipFm0?feat=embedwebsite"><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-KqYOjtYetuY/VBPdlSev4QI/AAAAAAAAE7Q/x507WauWmYs/s800/pkcs8encd.png" alt="encrypted private key" /></a>

  <p>Also, please note, AES is not the default algorithm for encrypting keys in openssl. The less secure, 3DES is the default, for openssl you must specify '-aes256' on the commandline to the genrsa or rsa command line applications.</p>
		]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://www.cem.me/20141221-cert-binaries-2.html</guid>
    </item>
      

    <item>
        <title>Certificate Binary Posters (Part One)</title>
        <link>https://www.cem.me/20141221-cert-binaries.html?s=r</link>
	<description><![CDATA[
  <p>To better understand the ins and outs of TLS certificates and the way they are stored in files, I decided to do a short series on the different PKCS (Public Key Cryptography Standards) that dissects each individual byte of the certificate or key file. This is part one which covers the public and private keys stored in the PKCS #1 format.</p>
  <p>The core and heart of a certificate are keys. Certificates utilize both public and private keys which are mathematically bound. The PKCS #1 standard includes both public and private key formats. The first step is to create the private key. Here is the way it's represented: on the top left - the binary file encoded in base64 (easiest for emailing or copy-pasting), below that - expanded into binary, and on the right - each byte expanded into what it means.</p>
  <a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/IBaE8vtc37W87HHgASU7l9MTjNZETYmyPJy0liipFm0?feat=embedwebsite"><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-71toRXOy-DI/VBPdlb4knJI/AAAAAAAAE7I/r8eBViG6z7E/s800/private%2520key.png" alt="private key" /></a>
  <p>The p and q are two random primes, e is an exponent used as part of the math, the value of e is typically the same across all certs. All of the other values are calculated based off of p, q, e and specific mathematical functions. n is the result of multiplying p and q, d is equal to e<sup>-1</sup> &#37; (n - (p + q -1)), all the other formulas are noted on the chart. The calculated values are all used extensively during crypto operations and are stored in the file to make those crypto operations faster.</p>
  <p>The public key, as stored in the PKCS#1 format starts off with a wrapper of two main sections, a descriptor of the algorithm and second, the bits in the public key. The descriptor holds the OID (Object IDentifier) of the encryption algorithm for which this key is to be used. The key includes same values that may look familiar: n and e, the multiplied primes used as the modulus and the exponent the message to encrypt is raised to the power of when encrypting.</p>
  <a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/lh/photo/8gkuddZIn1OAONZx9KQzltMTjNZETYmyPJy0liipFm0?feat=embedwebsite"><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-C40S_qivW34/VAZ_50rqpmI/AAAAAAAAE4Q/16xE0X3FsY0/s800/public%2520key.png" alt="public key" /></a>

		]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 06:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid>https://www.cem.me/20141221-cert-binaries.html</guid>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>HTTP DANE Validation Assertion</title>
        <link>https://www.cem.me/20141203-hdva.html?s=r</link>
        <description><![CDATA[
  <p>Certificates are typically authenticated via a chain of signatures that lead back to any one of a number of trusted roots. DNSSEC is validated much the same way, however, with DNSSEC there's only one root for delegating authority for the DNS while in certificates, any certificate authority can sign a certificate valid for any domain. There is a way to use this delegated system to verify connections made over TLS called DANE. In short, DANE is a way to use the DNSSEC to get signed records from an authoritative source to validate certificates used in TLS. You can see a great introduction to DANE by the working group co-chair here:<br /> <a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=emDxUQl1NvA">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=emDxUQl1NvA</a><br /> Also, some recent slides from a presentation by Dan York are here: <br /><a target="_blank" href="http://www.slideshare.net/Deploy360/3-dnssec-and-dane-ion-tokyo">http://www.slideshare.net/Deploy360/3-dnssec-and-dane-ion-tokyo</a>.</p>

  <p>In all things there is risk, there are ways to mitigate risk using controls, some are detective controls (CT) some are preventative (DANE, Public Key Pinning). Other's have developed many different ideas in how to ensure that the certificate that makes it to the client's browser is the one which the site owner intended. Some have done analysis of the different methods [<a target="_blank" href="https://mediatum.ub.tum.de/node?id=1182735">Ralph Holz</a>][<a target="_blank" href="http://queue.acm.org/detail.cfm?id=2668154">Ben Laurie</a>][<a target="_blank" href="http://www.scriptjunkie.us/2013/12/a-comparison-of-https-reforms/">Matt Weeks</a>]. A <a target="_blank" href="http://www.securityweek.com/convergence-replacement-throwdown-dane-vs-tack-vs-ct">SecurityWeek</a> article today even positions CT as a replacement for the preventive controls of TACK and DANE. I like certificate transparency (CT) as a way to detect CA compromise, but that is only after the fact (somthing I think that is not quite pointed out in the comparison chart at <a target="_blank" href="http://www.certificate-transparency.org/comparison">certificate-transparency.org</a> or in Ben's ACM article from above). However, for a real-time preventitive control, I prefer DANE.</p>

  <hr />
<p>Recently, I uploaded a draft to the IETF with the goal of furthering the adoption of DANE.<br />
<a target="_blank" href="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-cem-dane-assertion/">https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/draft-cem-dane-assertion/</a></p>

<p>Currently the adoption of DANE is lacking in browsers. The draft I wrote is to allow particular sites to declare themselves as ready to support DANE so that they can further lock down the security of their TLS connections. The method is to use an HTTP "Dane-Validation-Assertion" header or HDVA. I envision this as working as follows: A site sends the DVA header to a browser that tells the browser the browser will then do a lookup over DNSSEC for a TLSA (DANE) record to perform additional validations on the certificate.</p>

<p>Options for this header include the max time to keep/remember the assertion, a way to include subdomains, and a way to require a valid DANE response before continuing. The max-age and include-subdomains are used in the same manner as HTTP Strict Transport Security (HSTS</a>) and HTTP Public Key Pinning (HPKP</a>), the '<a href="http://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-cem-dane-assertion-00#section-2.1.3" target="_blank">require</a>' however, is a concept specific HDVA. The reason I included this directive was because the way DANE works; if you receive a certificate that is valid through the regular means of validating using certificate authorities (PKIX) and do not receive any DANE records, the connection will continue. By using the 'require' directive, the server operator forces the connection to be validated using the traditional method of CAs accompanied by DANE or solely by using DANE.</p>


	]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 4 Dec 2014 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <guid>https://www.cem.me/20141203-hdva.html</guid>
</item>

    <item>
        <title>iOS 8.1 and CVE-2014-4449</title>
        <link>https://www.cem.me/papers/cve-2014-4449.html?s=r</link>
        <description><![CDATA[
  <p>Today, Apple released security advisory <a href="http://support.apple.com/en-us/HT203119" target="_blank">APPLE-SA-2014-10-20-1</a> for iOS 8.1 that includes <a href="https://web.nvd.nist.gov/view/vuln/detail?vulnId=CVE-2014-4449" target="_blank">CVE-2014-4449</a>.</p>
  <p>This relates to a TLS certificate validation vulnerability in the clients accessing iCloud affecting bookmarks, calendar, tasks, and possibly other data types allowing for modification and disclosure of data.</p>
  <p>Exposure of sensitive reminders, meetings, bookmarks (including bookmarklets that could allow logins to other saved websites). Users may store sensitive data within these data objects that are synced to iCloud, these are at risk of exposure through this vulnerability.</p>
  <dl>
  <dt><b>Data Disclosed Includes:</b></dt>
  <dd>User Display Name</dd>
  <dd>Apple DAV Push Token</dd>
  <dd>Owner ID</dd>
  <dd>X-MobileMe-Auth Token (encoded in b64, prepended Owner ID)</dd>
  <dd>Push Key (prepended Owner ID)</dd>
  <dd>DAV Sync Token</dd>
  <dd>
   <dl>
    <dt><b>The full gziped text of the following data types:</b></dt>
    <dd>Reminders</dd>
    <dd>Calendar Events</dd>
    <dd>Safari Bookmarks</dd>
   </dl>
  </dd>
  </dl>
  
  <dl>
  <dt><b>Connections not validated include:</b></dt>
  <dd>p11-caldav.icloud.com</dd>
  <dd>p11-bookmarks.icloud.com</dd>
  </dl>
  <pre>
<code>
Vulnerability Disclosure Timeline:
==================================
2014-07-15:     Researcher discovery
2014-07-16:     Vendor Notification
2014-07-17:     Vendor Confirmation of reciept of report
2014-10-02:     Vendor Response/Feedback
2014-10-20:     Vendor Fix/Patch
2014-10-20:     Public Disclosure

Impact
==================================
CVSS Severity (version 2.0):
CVSS v2 Base Score: 6.8 (MEDIUM)
Impact Subscore: 6.4
Exploitability Subscore: 8.6
CVSS Version 2 Metrics:
Access Vector: Network exploitable
Access Complexity: Medium
Authentication: Not required to exploit
Impact Type: Allows unauthorized disclosure of
    information; Allows unauthorized modification;
    Allows disruption of service
</code>
  </pre>

  <p><i>--speculation ahead--</i><br />According to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cwmmLRUYaQ8" target="_blank">ElcomSoft</a>, a Russian mobile forensics company, the data gathered from the MobileMe-Auth Token might be able to be used to get additional authentication tokens as well as a number of other interesting things like iOS iCloud backups. These are encrypted using retrievable keys that are also stored in the cloud.</p>
  <p>So, assumedly, one executing an attack on CVE-2014-4449, would have the ability to not only see just the data going over the unauthenticated streams to the calendar, reminders, and bookmarks, but also could pivot those authentication keys to download and decrypt backups of iOS devices. Once a backup is retrieved and decrypted the attacker has access to all of the iPhone data using a variety of free or paid tools for forensic analysis.</p>

  ]]>
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <guid>https://www.cem.me/papers/cve-2014-4449.html</guid>
        </item>

   </channel>
</rss>

